Syed Tanveer Hussain

tanveer1807@yahoo.com +92 308 8970987 E11, Islamabad, Pakistan Islamabad, Punjab

Summary

A Hobbyist forward-thinking developer offering upto 3 years of experience building, integrating, testing and supporting Android

applications for mobile and tablet devices on the Android platform seeks position with a top technology firm and moreover i feel pleasure in building applications.

Experience

Android Developer

NokNok • Islamabad, Capitol Territory

08/2021 - Present

- Basically NokNok is the child company of the iengineering Pakistan group. it is grocery delivery platform that make sure the fastest delivery of goods across lebanon.
- My job is to maintain their android stack of infrastructure.
- Since i am interseted in Devops I also help the team in day to day maintance of the server infrastructure over GCP kubernetes engine.

Android Developer

9Sol Technologies • Islamabad, Capitol Territory

12/2020 - 05/2021

- At 9sol technologies my responsibilites were to develop playstore base apps and update the existing code from previous developers.
- conducting technical interviews of the candidates.
- leave the company due to managerial issues.

Android Developer

9D Technologies • Rawalpindi, Punjab

06/2019 - 01/2021

- Here I worked on maintaining already developed products from the previous employees and also gave updates if necessary.
- · Also i build them many apps and worth mentioning three apps that are highly downloaded and top ranked
- Recently worked on instagram saver and it gone viral on the playstore and it's ranked one of the top easy, usable and highly rated app. it is the fastest downloader in the category.

Junior Android Developer

Jolta Technologies • Rawalpindi, Punjab

12/2018 - 03/2019

- Worked as a junior android developer and build few playstore oriented apps.
- I had to leave the company ealry due to relocation problems.

Android Developer

IT Gems • Faisalabad, Punjab

04/2018 - 10/2018

- An acquaintance wanted me to help him grow his buisness and i joined him for some time as an android developer.
- I built android apps there and he distributed it to the local clients and also put them for sale online.
- As my University tenure ended I had to leave as we aggreed.

Android Developer

AlBattar Solutions • Faisalabad, Punjab 08/2017 - 12/2017

• Built an app for automotive service providers so that they can reach their clients on time and provide gas or make a repair.

Skills

Android, Android SDK, Kotlin, Java, Node & Express. Js, App Architecture and Design

Education

Engineering

Islamia college peshawar • Peshawar, KPK 02/2014

• At the time my love and curiosity for philosphy was very high and in the local departmental competition of philosphy - Engineering student won the prize.

Engineering

Government College University Faisalabad • Faisalabad, Punjab 02/2018

• Apart from other activities i am the only guy that got 'A' grade in almost all the programming exams and competitions

Languages

Urdu, English

Some Extra Stuff About Me

Github

https://github.com/tanoDxyz

Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-tanveer-hussain-631134ba/